Russell Hancox

Curriculum Vitae

© 07595 038 535 □ russell@hancox.us □ russell.hancox.us

A skilled problem-solver, capable of generating viable solutions utilising significant hardware and software expertise. Energetic and dynamic, relishes challenges, demonstrates in-depth analytical ability and learns new skills very quickly.

Professional Experience

2007-Present

Genius, Apple, Birmingham, UK.

Within this role, the following tasks are undertaken:

- + Assisting customers in resolving technical issues with their Apple products at the Genius Bar, ensuring that every customer leaves with an acceptable solution
- + Turning around repairs to customers as quickly as possible while at the same time ensuring that every repair that is done has been completed to the highest standard
- + Documenting all interactions thoroughly and concisely

2009–2010 **Software Engineer (Intern)**, *IBM*, Hursley, UK.

Spent a year working at IBM's Hursley software development lab as a member of the build team for WebSphere MQ. The role:

- + Required becoming familiar with a complex assortment of scripts and systems, the layout of the complex MQ codebase and a number of different platforms.
- + Responsible for ensuring the successful builds of several versions of WMQ across 12 platforms in both service and development streams
- + Helped maintain and extend the automated build infrastructure
- + Supported developers with determining the cause of build failures and providing debugging information where appropriate
- + Developed a solution to simplify an existing sandbox build solution and integrated a targeted testing system
- + Assisted with the development of an automated deletion mechanism for service builds on the IBM i operating system
- + Worked on a complex project to report the status of build machines on all of the platforms using Java, EJB and MQ.

2006-2007

Network Support Engineer, Evesham Technology, Evesham, UK.

Accountable for a variety of tasks to meet business demand; requiring significant versatility whilst:

- + Responding to correspondence addressed to the business support help desk including: emails & faxes together with answering incoming support calls and performing call-back requests from other departments
- + Assisting Installation Engineers with advanced fault finding and system configuration as required
- + Troubleshooting router and/or firewall issues including Cisco PIX Firewalls and VPN issues.
- + Using remote communications to assist clients with enterprise antivirus updates, software or hardware problem resolution on servers and workstations, backup problem solving or email problems.
- + Where remote communication is not required or unavailable, utilising strong communication skills together with knowledge of operating systems, applications and hardware to resolve problems over the phone
- + Aiding with the support/administration of large Managed Service networks

Skills

Objective-C, PHP, Perl, Java, C Programming

Cocoa, iOS, POSIX, Git, Subversion, EJB, Servlets **Technologies**

Xcode, Eclipse Environments

> Mac OS X, Linux, *BSD, Solaris, AIX, HP-UX, IBM i, Windows (3.1-7), Windows Operating

Systems Server (2000–2008), MS-DOS

Software Microsoft Exchange 2000-2008, Apache 2, WebSphere MQ, MySQL, Cisco PIX OS,

Microsoft Office, Apple iWork, Lotus Notes, LATEX

Education

2007-2011 Software Engineering, Birmingham City University, Birmingham, UK.

(In Progress) Selection of Modules Taken: Programming Languages & Techniques, Concurrent & Realtime

Systems, Systems Software & Utilities, Applied Systems Engineering, Networks for Business,

Top-Down Network Design

Apple Certified Macintosh Technician, Apple. 2008

Interests

I enjoy programming as a hobby and regularly work on small projects at home to Programming & Electronics

learn new skills. I have recently become interested in electronics and embedded

programming thanks to the the Arduino and Mbed platforms

I fly R/C helicopters, a very challenging but rewarding hobby R/C Helicopters

Motorbikes I'm a keen motorcyclist, commuting daily in all weathers and recreational riding in

fair weather

References

References available on request